JAMES LEWIS

Unit 2/43 Strathalbyn St, Kew East · 0422732175

Jamesglew@gmail.com · LinkedIn Profile · Github

Junior software developer with a passion for user centered design principles. I aim to provide the best possible experience for users and the client.

EXPERIENCE

March 2022 - December 2022

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER, MOJO CROWE.

Product owner for the new website www.mojocrowe.com which involved:

- Managing PRs
- Working with a designer and figma designs to get the most accurate product
- Front End Development with React, React-Router, Material UI and Apollo-Graphql(100% of the website was coded by myself)
- Creation of required endpoints using MySQL and Graphql
- Managing Tickets, timeline and feedback throughout the project
- Optimized for all mobile sizes down to 375px Width
- Designed as a SSR website using After.js to improve performance
- Created a finite state machine for a non-deployed version of the website contact page

Custom Material UI component library:

- Created a custom UI component library using Material UI and Storybook
- Adapting Material Base components to fit designs from figma
- Bundling the library using a monorepo to make it accessible to each other project for the company
- Received and implemented UI designer feedback

Teams Admin Portal:

- Created the base functionality for a Vite.js based admin portal
- Front End Development using React, Typescript, React-Router, Vite.js, Custom UI library and Apollo-graphql
- Managing tickets, timeline, PRs and feedback
- Created and edited end points from a MySQL Database and graphql to extend and improve functionality
- Optimized for mobile with different layouts/navigation and functionality

Other Responsibilities:

- Sitting in on major strategy meetings and interviews for the development team to grow the company
- Updating and reporting to the CEO, Design Team and Socials team

•

August 2021 - March 2022

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER, PING Co.

Sole frontend developer maintaining and extending a networking portal:

- Maintaining a React, Redux, React-Router application
- Extending functionality based on requirements from the sales team
- Refactoring and improving the code quality and readability
- Working with the sales team and CEO to determine time frames for features and providing progress bi-weekly reports.

June **2021 -** August **2021**

UI/UX AND FRONTEND DEVELOPER, UNEEK

Frontend and UI/UX development using React, Typescript and Material UI.

FEBRUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

UI/UX AND FRONTEND DEVELOPER, DIGITIZATION OF ABORIGINAL HISTORY PROJECT

UI/UX DESIGNER

User experience designer for final year project.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Front end development using android studio and kotlin.

JANUARY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016

FIBRE OPTIC NETWORK DESIGNER, BIARRI NETWORKS

PRODUCT TESTING
PROJECT PLANNING & TEAM LEADERSHIP
CLIENT LIAISON

EDUCATION

FEBRUARY 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science, Swinburne University of Technology Majoring in Software Development and co-majoring in Cyber Security

November 2014

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, SWINBURNE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY Majoring in Biochemistry and co-majoring in Advanced Chemistry

SKILLS

- Kotlin
- C++/C#
- Python
- CSS/HTML
- UI/UX Design
- Material UI
- Git
- Agile Development

- Project Management
- Team Leadership Experience
- Technical Writing & Presentation
- Client Relations
- GIS Data Systems
- Cisco Certified Network Associate
- 120 WPM Typing Speed

- SQL Databases
- Graphql
- Android Development
- React

REFERENCES

References will be provided if requested.